Roscoe Drummond Papers
Roscoe Drummond Papers
1967-1970
Drummond, Roscoe, 1902-1983.
1.4 linear ft.
Papers of the American newspaper columnist. Correspondence and writings, including newspaper columns (1967-1970), drafts, revisions, clippings.
148954
Biographical History
J. Roscoe Drummond (1902-1983) was an American journalist, editor and syndicated Washington columnist. Born in Theresa, New York, he graduated from Syracuse University and went on to write for national publications including the Christian Science Monitor, the New York Herald Tribune, and the Los Angeles Times Syndicate. He was chief of the Washington Bureau for both the Monitor (1940-1953) and the Herald Tribune, and his "State of the Nation" column was carried by 150 newspapers across the country. From 1949-1951 he served as European Director of Information for the Marshall Plan. He is also remembered for his vocal opposition to censorship.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Roscoe Drummond Papers consist of correspondence and writing.
Correspondence contains three letters, with enclosures, including one from San Francisco mayor Joseph L. Alioto.
Writings are made up of columns written, for the most part, by Drummond; those after 1968 were written with his son Geoffrey. There are also a few columns written by Saville Davis, Carleton Kent, Tom Littlewood, Earl Mazo, Philip Potter, and Thomas Ross, each of whom substituted for Drummond on occasion. Some of these have specific titles and appear to have been nationally syndicated, while those entitled "Point of View" may have been written for a single publication. Usually there are several revised drafts of each column; these, along with associated research material, clippings or press releases, are filed together.
Arrangement of the Collection
With the exception of one folder of miscellaneous research material, which could not be placed with a specific column, the writings are arranged alphabetically by author and within that chronologically.
Related Material
has more than eighty collections relating to journalists and journalism; please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Drummond, Roscoe, 1902-1983.; Journalism.; Journalists -- United States.; Newspapers --Sections, columns, etc.; Drafts (documents); Newspaper columns.; Journalists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Roscoe Drummond, 1970.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - 1967-1969 (Box 1)
- Writings
  - Research material
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Columns
    - Davis, Saville, Aug 1967, Dec 1967, Jan 1968; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Drummond, Roscoe
      - Jan 1967-Feb 1968, 8 folders (Box 1)
      - Mar 1968-Dec 1969, 10 folders (Box 2)
      - Jan 1970-Jun 1970, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Kent, Carleton, Dec 1967 (Box 3)
    - Littlewood, Tom, Sep 1967, Jan 1968; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Mazo, Earl, Aug 1967 (Box 3)
    - Potter, Philip, Sep 1967, Dec 1967 (Box 3)
    - Ross, Thomas, Dec 1967, Jan 1968; 2 folders (Box 3)